Guide to the Thomas Henick-Kling papers.
Henick-Kling, Thomas papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Thomas Henick-Kling papers 1961-2002
22-2-3604
Thomas. Henick-Kling
3 cubic feet.
Correspondence, Publications, Research Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection consits of papers from his work at the NYSAES in Geneva, NY. Most are related to wine and grapes. Areas covered include New York, California, Germany, and others. Contains research materials, presentations, brochures, and slides.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Henick-Kling served as a professor in the department of food science and technology at the New York State Agricultural Experiment Station in Geneva, NY. Other posts include director of the National Wine and Grape Industry Centre at Charles Stuart University in New South Wales, Australia and at Cornell University, he directed the Wine Laboratory and Data Bank and organized the annual Wine Industry Workshop.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection consits of papers from his work at the NYSAES in Geneva, NY. Most are related to wine and grapes. Areas covered include New York, California, Germany, and others. Contains research materials, presentations, brochures, and slides.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Henick-Kling, Thomas.; New York State Agricultural Experiment Station.
Subjects:
Viticulture--Europe.; Grape industry--New York (State).; Viticulture--New York (State).; Wine and wine making.; Viticulture.; Grapes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Forms part of the Eastern Wine and Grape Archive. (EWGA)
CONTAINER LIST
- Wine & Grape Research at Cornell University (Box 1, Folder 1)
- International Wineries (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Wine in New York (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Studies by Cornell University (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Wine Lab Stat. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Analysis of Wine (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Analysis of Wine-Overheads (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Wine Analytical Lab. Sheets (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bacterial in wine perception (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Technical Services (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Lab result (Box 1, Folder 11)
- UC Davis Wine Courses (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Geneva Country Club Wine Dinner, 17 Nov 01 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Slides (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Geisenheim Student, Sept 01 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- ASEV-ES 11-13 July, 01, July 11-13, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- FIS Meeting, June 11-14, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- AOAC Meeting 7-8 June, 01, June 7-8, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- ICCS 2000 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Viticulture 2000 Meeting-Buffalo, February 17-18, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Oesterreich, April 3-7, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Groupe Polyphenols, Weihenstephan, Sept 2000 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Burgundy Tour, May 2000 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- CIFS Advisory Committee Meeting, April 25-26, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Vinitaly 16-20 April, 98, April 16-20, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Burgundy Seminar 6-11 Feb, 99, February 6-11, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Intervitis 14-17 May, 98 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Symposium in Santa Rosa, CA, April 15, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- NY State Wine Competition, August 8, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- ACS WNY December 1997 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Cool Climate, Hotel Reservation, July 1996 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- ACS San Francisco April 15-16, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Oenology Workshop, March 7, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Riesling Symposium 1997 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Central Washington Wine Technical Group Short Course, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Wine Industry-Technical Advisory Panel, 1961-1968 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  Grape and Wine Research
- Wine Industry-Technical Advisory Panel, 1974- (Box 1, Folder 37)
  Grape and Wine Research at the New York State Agriucltural Experiment Station Cornell University, Geneva, New York
- Record Book, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Wine Workshop, Community College of Finger Lakes (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Papers from UC Davis (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Cornell Institue of Food Science (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Slides about wineries and distillation (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Record Book (Box 1, Folder 43)
- American Society of Enology and Viticulture Board of Directors Reference Guide (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Australia-Wine Brochures and Pamphlets (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Italy-Wine Brochures and Pamphlets (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Canada-Wine Brochures and Pamphlets (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Greece, Cyprus, Spain and Hungary-Wine Brochures and Pamphlets (Box 2, Folder 4)
- France-Wine Brochures and Pamphlets 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- France-Wine Brochures and Pamphlets 2 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Germany-Wine Brochures and Pamphlets 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Germany-Wine Brochures and Pamphlets 2 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Germany-Wine Brochures and Pamphlets 3 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Germany-Wine Brochures and Pamphlets 4 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- California-Wine Brochures and Pamphlets (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Oregon and Washington-Wine Brochures and Pamphlets (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Wine Catalogues-Germany (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Courses in Brewing Science at Oregon State University, June 9-11, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Proposal for New Degree Major, Bachelor of Science in Wine & Viticulture, at California Polytechnic State University, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Paper by Thomas Henick-Kling, June 1996 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Finger Lakes Pinot Noir Alliance-Tasting Notes, December 2000 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- The International Wine Symposium 1994 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- 13th International Enology Symposium-Powerpoint Printout, 9-12 June, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Ernst Moschle (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Nomacorc (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Foss Instruments (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Invitation to hold the 5th Int'l Symposium on Cool Climate Viticulture and Oenology (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Thomas Henick-Kling-Two Decades in Wine (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Correspondences and Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Finger Lakes Pinot Noir Alliance-Tasting Notes (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Wine and Grape Program at Cornell (Box 3, Folder 14)
- New York State Wine Industry (Box 3, Folder 15)
- New York Wineries 1 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- New York Wineries 2 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Finger Lakes Wineries 1 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Finger Lakes Wineries 2 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Finger Lakes Wineries 3 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- New York Grape and Wine Foundation 1 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- New York Grape and Wine Foundation 2 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Wineries in other states (Box 3, Folder 23)
- International Merlot Symposium, July 6-7, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Wine Business and Marketing Seminar, July 2002 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Wine Catalog by Vitro Packaging (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Origins of Cayuga White, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Wine and Juice Grape Varieties for Cool Climates (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Good Morning America segment featuring Orley Ashenfelter and his computer prediction model of what vintages are best using weather data. Thomas Henick-Kling also appears in the segment. 2 copies., March 9, 1995; V-1109, V-1110